About Privacy ❮ Previous Next ❯ Privacy Statement for W3Schools

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from w3schools.com (the "Site").

Personal information we collect

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as "Device Information".

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

*   "Cookies" are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org.
*   "Log files", and User Accounts, track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.
*   "Web beacons", "tags", and "pixels" are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

Additionally when you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain information from you, including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card numbers, email address, and phone number. We refer to this information as "Order Information".

Personal User Information

When we talk about "Personal Information" in this Privacy Policy, we are talking both about Device Information and Order Information.

How do we use your personal information?  
We use the Order Information that we collect generally to fulfill any orders placed through the Site (including processing your payment information, arranging for shipping, and providing you with invoices and/or order confirmations). Additionally, we use this Order Information to:

*   Communicate with you.
*   Screen our orders for potential risk or fraud. and
*   When in line with the preferences you have shared with us, provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services.

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

We use your account information that we collect generally to generate statistics for you, and provide personalized roadmaps. Additionally, we use this information to:

*   Communicate with you.
*   When in line with the preferences you have shared with us, provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services.

Sharing you personal Information

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above.

For example, we use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site -- you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

We also use Shopify to power our online store--you can read more about how Shopify uses your Personal Information here: https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy.

We fund our site by showing adverts as you browse our site. These adverts are usually managed by a partner specializing in providing adverts for multiple sites. Invariably these partners collect anonymous data about the websites you visits so they can personalize the adverts to you, ensure that you don't see the same adverts too frequently and ultimately report to advertisers on which adverts are working.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

Behavioural advertising

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative's ("NAI") educational page at http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

You can opt out of targeted advertising by using the links below:

*   \- Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads
*   \- Google: https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous
*   \- Bing: https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads

You can get a full list of the partners we use by accessing our ads.txt file.

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance's opt-out portal at: http://optout.aboutads.info/.

You can learn more about online advertising, or opt-out of almost all advertising cookies at https://www.youronlinechoices.com.

**Note:** Opting out will not disable ads, they will just no longer be tailored to you.

Manage Consent

If you want to change your choices regarding your personal information, you can use the button below:

Manage Consent

Do not track

Please note that we do not alter our Site's data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

Your rights

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the contact information below.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.

Data retention

When you place an order through the Site, we will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

Changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

Using Google Drive in our Tryit Editor

Our Tryit Editor allows users to store code to, or import code from, Google Drive.

This allows users to:

*   Store examples/code to their Google Drive
*   Share examples/code through Google Drive

W3Schools does not keep for ourselves, or share this information with third parties.

Links

W3Schools contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. This privacy document applies only to W3Schools.

Contact us

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by e‑mail at help@w3schools.com or by mail using the details provided below:

w3schools  
\[Re: Privacy Compliance Officer\]  
Larsamyraa 18, 4313 SANDNES, Norway

❮ Previous Next ❯
